Soundboard: Friends with Brews!
Scott: Friends with Rogue Amoeba? It's working this time, Peter. Oh my god.
Peter: I also am friends with Rogue Amoeba on the piezo side.
Scott: Yep. I'm friends with them on the audio hijack side and this time my
Scott: levels appear to be working so I don't have to use the f-word and find my clinky thing.
Peter: The f-word.
Scott: It wasn't the f-word. I called him an a-word.
Peter: Speaking of clinky things, what are we clinking today?
Scott: Oh yeah, you go first because you're... oh look at that.
Scott: That looks like a bottle of kombucha or something weird.
Peter: It is not. This is a bottle of Hackerschor Oktoberfestmarzen Original Filter German Fest
Peter: Beer because it is Oktoberfest season. Drink that because you're not a hacker.
Peter: I am indeed a hacker. You're the anti-hacker.
Peter: I'm an ethical hacker.
Peter: All right, I got a little bit of a pop there. I dropped the case and now I'm pouring.
Peter: Oh yeah.
Scott: Oh yeah, look at that.
Peter: What about you? What are you drinking?
Scott: I'm having a repeat, Peter. I'm having a Three Creeks chocolate pine porter.
Peter: Chocolate porter? Five pine chocolate porter.
Scott: But I'm also having a new coffee.
Peter: Oh.
Scott: I'm having what is called a Dapper and Wise Roasters highbrow blend.
Peter: Oh, a highbrow blend.
Scott: It says nutty, filbert's, dates.
Scott: Then it says whole bean and it says comforting.
Scott: It's comforting, Peter. It doesn't matter what you say to me today.
Scott: I'm going to be comforted by my highbrow blend.
Peter: Well, you should keep that along. Well, cheers buddy.
Scott: Cheers my friend. Oh, I haven't poured my beer yet though. Geez.
Peter: What are you waiting for? Man, holding me up.
Scott: I only do one thing at a time. I can't hold you up even though you're probably lighter than I am.
Scott: For sure you are.
Scott: But remember I have a bad shoulder. Actually, my shoulder is pretty good these days.
Peter: Mine has been acting up and I haven't been doing my physical therapy as regular as I should,
Peter: but I'm going to have to start doing my physical therapy again for my knee
Peter: because that is aggravated. Well, but on that note, first happy thoughts. Cheers.
Scott: Cheers my friend.
Scott: Yeah, I found that my shoulder, if I do my PT and or body weight strength exercises
Scott: three times a week, that's enough to keep my shoulder feeling really good.
Peter: Okay.
Scott: I try to do it more, but I'm just saying at a minimum,
Scott: at a very minimum twice a week, but I need to average three times a week
Scott: to really keep it from feeling pain and then it feels really good. So.
Peter: Yeah, I can tell when I've been lacking and I've been, I've definitely been lacking in my,
Peter: my, my PT exercises, but yeah, I was getting a massage last week and it was a Thai massage.
Peter: And at the end, the girl was working on it, you know, like basically hyper compressed my knee
Peter: a little bit and feels like it sort of re-aggravated the injury from almost a year ago.
Scott: I hate to tell you, but that wasn't a girl that was giving you a massage,
Scott: Peter. In Thailand, they have elephants and they put them to good use.
Peter: No, I get to, if it was an elephant, they wouldn't have been working on my knees.
Peter: It would have been different.
Scott: Just leave your deposit in the trunk, Peter.
Peter: Thank you.
Scott: No problem.
Peter: Oh my God.
Scott: Oh man.
Peter: Have we ever got a lot to talk about?
Scott: Oh, well let's do it.
Peter: All right.
Peter: So first off, so you, you're doing, you, you're doing, you're doing a repeat beer,
Peter: but mine is a new beer.
Scott: Yeah. So talk about it. Tell us about the flavors. What notes do you taste?
Peter: It is malty. It is toasty and it is crisp, but it is nice.
Peter: It's like a five, I want to say a 5.6% alcohol.
Scott: Of course I hold it up to the mic.
Scott: No, I see it, but let me see it in the glass.
Scott: I want to see the color, the beautiful color.
Peter: Oh, it is a nice coppery.
Scott: That is nice.
Peter: Coppery color.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: My beer is 6.2% alcohol by volume.
Scott: If you will recall my chocolate porter.
Scott: Here's what mine looks like. Very dark, very dark.
Scott: Definitely nice malty flavor.
Peter: Nice.
Peter: Very mild hoppy, you know, bitterness. It's, it's very tolerable. So this is a Marsen.
Peter: Apparently it's part of a category like a Vienna lager or German style Marsen.
Peter: Apparently there's similarities there. So, but a nice deep amber color and it's very clear.
Peter: It's filtered. So it's, you know, very crisp and clear. You can see right through it.
Scott: It looks good.
Peter: Very happy. This is, this is good.
Scott: I can see right through your beer, Peter.
Scott: Yeah, this is good. I've talked about this beer before, but it's a good chocolate.
Scott: Sometimes when people put chocolate in beer, they go way overboard.
Peter: Yes.
Scott: This is not overboard. I didn't have to throw it overboard. They didn't go overboard.
Scott: There's no overboards in this beer.
Peter: Don't throw your beer overboard. That has to be really bad. I mean, you have to be desperate.
Scott: There's no overboarding. There's no waterboarding. It's just beer.
Scott: It's just chocolate beer and it's good.
Peter: Chocolate beer. We like that.
Scott: Yep. So what do we have? Oh, and the coffee is really good too. Let me take a
Scott: sip of this and see what I think of this highbrow blend.
Scott: There's not a brand that we're accustomed to buying this. What did I call it? Kettle and wise
Scott: Sanford and sons, dapper and wise, dapper and wise. It's very dapper. And it's very wise.
Peter: Indeed.
Scott: It's a pretty good coffee. I don't know if it's my favorite, but it's up there. It's
Scott: nice and smooth. There is no bitterness to it. Yeah, it's good.
Scott: I definitely smell the nuttiness and I taste it.
Peter: It's like taste the rainbow.
Scott: You know, it's Oh, speaking of that, I have, I got a book. Have I got an excerpt from a book
Scott: for you, but before we get there, let's talk about what we're watching. And by that, I mean,
Scott: what we're risking watching on our wrists on our watch. As we watch our wrists.
Peter: As I understand it, we are both watching Apple watch ultra twos.
Scott: You are correct. Very good. First of all, one thing I would like to find out from you is how
Scott: you have your watch face set up and I will send you a picture of mine.
Peter: I'm using the same face that you are, but it's with a slightly different configuration.
Scott: Right, right. It's the only that's the problem is I turn it slightly. You're not,
Scott: you're finding all the wrong angles. Ooh, that's way different. Take a screenshot of it and send
Scott: it to me. I'm sending you a screenshot of mine right now. This is mine, but I used the Apple
Scott: frames shortcut that Vittici made. So that's why it has the actual wristwatch around it.
Peter: There's an Apple frames shortcut?
Scott: Yeah. It auto detects what the screenshot came from, what device the screenshot came from,
Scott: and it puts a frame around it. Oh, that's pretty cool.
Peter: It is cool. What does that cost?
Scott: No, it's free. Oh, you just got to go to max stories.net and search for frames shortcut.
Peter: Well, you should put that into the show notes. I should. And I will, but right now I'm drinking
Scott: beer and coffee and I really don't want to search for it myself. Fine. Be that way.
Scott: Yeah. So I bought an Apple watch ultra two because my Apple watch six battery was starting to,
Scott: to use itself up on a very rapid basis every day. And, and I would have to charge quite a bit before
Scott: I could work out at night. If I was working out at night, it would drain like crazy during the day.
Scott: And I was worried about having enough battery at work. Sometimes I thought, you know, I should get
Scott: an Apple watch ultra because I want the longer battery. And what I figured I would like is what
Scott: I do like one of the things that I like, which is I can work out for a couple hours during the day,
Scott: any time of day. And I don't think about charging. I don't care what my battery percentage is that I
Scott: just do my fricking workouts for as long as I want without even thinking about it. That is so nice.
Peter: And that goes to like the conversations that people have around electric vehicles,
Peter: where most people who have electric vehicles would be perfectly fine suited, just fine with a car
Peter: that has a hundred mile range, but it just feels nicer to have a 300 mile range, right? You know,
Peter: just to have that little extra in the tank. So same with the watch. And like I said, there have been
Scott: times where if I've been at work and then I'm going to work out at night, I definitely have
Scott: to spot charge to make sure that I have enough battery to get through the workout. Yep. I probably
Scott: could have gotten by some of those times without spot charging, but I would have been in the red by
Scott: the time I got done working out. So why do that? I like the size. It's perfect. Got the trail.
Scott: I guess this is the trail band, but it's kind of weird. The fine woven trail loop. I like it.
Scott: Yeah. This is the eco one that took three. This is why my watch took so long to get was because
Peter: this is supposed to be environmentally friendly. Right. Well, environmentally friendly means it
Scott: costs more and takes more time to make. Right. And I also have worn some of my other bands that
Scott: I've owned previously with it and they fit fine and they're nice too. So I've got multiple bands.
Scott: Man, the display is so much better. The flat display, not having that dumb curve in it at
Scott: the top and sides, it just, it looks higher quality. It's shinier. The screen is more
Scott: legible. It's brighter. The flatness helps with usability. It looks like what the Apple watch
Peter: should have been to me. Right. But if the original Apple watch had been $800, they probably wouldn't
Scott: have sold as many. Well, and that's the downside to getting into the ultra lifestyle is now I've
Scott: got all the benefits, but every upgrade is going to cost over double, you know, or roughly double,
Peter: whatever, somewhere in that range. Unless they ever, you know, be think maybe, maybe by the
Peter: time Apple watch series 10 comes out, they might actually increase the battery life. Yeah. But
Scott: it's not just the battery life that I care about. Like I said, the display, there's no comparison.
Scott: I would never go back to that other display. Yeah, no, absolutely. I'm definitely happier
Scott: with the ultra. The buttons are nice. They yellow button, the orange button. What's that called?
Scott: The action button, the action button. I haven't really figured out why it's there. It's kind of
Peter: useless. I struggle to use it. I use that action cut shortcut that you turned me on to a while ago,
Peter: but it was so slow. Yeah. It took like many seconds to do whatever it was ever going to do.
Peter: And I got tired of waiting for it. Did you try it on the ultra too though? I don't know that I did
Peter: give it a try on that. See if it's any different. Yeah. Right now I just have it set to me. My
Peter: I drank water shortcut tracking when I make sure that's a good idea. I just use it to open workouts,
Scott: which I don't know why, because I've got many other ways to easily get into workouts,
Scott: but it's just whatever. I guess I could make it flashlight or, uh, have you tried the emergency
Peter: 95 decibel, uh, siren alarm shortcut? I have not be curious to hear what it sounds like.
Scott: Yeah. I would. I bet my cats would too. Yeah. I should do that now. See what it sounds like
Scott: right in the microphone. Yeah. The screen is amazing. The buttons are nice. One thing I had
Scott: originally when I first started using it was I would roll the crown to scroll things, right?
Scott: And then if I wanted to roll back in the other direction, I found that I was pushing the button
Scott: right into my wrist. That button is like right on the wrist and it was digging into my wrist
Scott: and it hurt. Now I can do it without even compressing the watch whatsoever. But at first
Scott: I thought this is going to be a serious problem. As it turns out, it's not. I just scrubbed the
Scott: crown a little bit differently, but I noticed now that that means that I'm using the crown differently
Scott: than I was on my Apple watch six. And I had to, cause that one's in the center of the watch,
Scott: right? Not at the top of the watch. All right. So that annoyed me at first, but I got over it now.
Scott: I don't even have that problem. So I don't know what that was all about.
Scott: Good. Yeah. It's speedy stuff launches quick. I'm hoping that like podcasts and stuff will download
Scott: to this watch faster than they did on my Apple watch six. Hmm. I don't know about that. Oh yeah.
Scott: I don't know. It might, I just honestly don't know. But I mean, I've got cellular enabled as well. So
Peter: how about offline Siri? I don't know. I don't know. I can't tell you. I, one thing I did
Scott: notice today and I sent you a message about it was even with the water eject feature,
Scott: for some reason on this watch, when I try to tell it stuff through the mic, you know, when I
Scott: tell it things after I've been in the shower, it gets everything wrong for a little while.
Scott: It's like, there's water in there. It's so weird. It is freaking weird. And then it works again,
Scott: just fine later. And I haven't quite figured that one out. Have you noticed anything like that?
Peter: No, I haven't really. I've gotten it wet from time to actually know this watch. I don't even
Peter: remember if I've gotten this one wet or not. I don't think I've. Wait, you don't shower. See,
Scott: I have, what do they call those? The sport band, the rubbery ones. I use those when working out
Scott: because I don't want to get this one. I don't want to sweat stain this. And so I wear those
Scott: when working out. And so I just help in the shower with my watch on. Oh, okay. Why not get all the
Peter: grime and sweat off it? Why not? Yeah, I don't know. I usually just take it off and that's one
Peter: of the, you know, one of the times that it spends charging. Peter, the advantage of being in a
Scott: beautiful relationship with your watches, you can shower with it. Uh, I'm sure it is. Anyway,
Scott: I like it. It's good. It's definitely a notable upgrade. I understand why people like there so
Scott: much. I kind of forgive all the people who never actually workout with their ultra watches. Although I'm sure
Scott: that in the four and a half days that I've owned mine, I've already put more exercise minutes on
Scott: it than probably 90% of the middle-aged white guys out there that own ultra watches. Probably. Yes.
Peter: I mean, you be careful. You might be talking to some of our tens of listeners here. I know. And
Scott: I'm sorry, but get your ass out there and exercise. Oh man. All right. What else? So you've got your
Peter: watch. That's good. It's big. It's beautiful, et cetera. You've still got yours. I've still got mine.
Peter: Yup. And I've got speechify. You've talked about that before, but it sounds like you're
getting even more into it than you were before. I'm getting a little more into it, but with every
Peter: step that I get into it, I find more limitations. And it's so weird. It's such a weird company. It's
Peter: a small, it's gotta be a small group of developers. It can't be, you know, this is not a huge program.
And the thing is that, you know, it's saving grace over all of the other text to speech stuff that I
have used as the voices, as I've mentioned, right? The voices are great. I can listen to these voices
for a long time. Well, I mean, they've got Gwyneth Paltrow. And Snoop Dogg. Don't forget Snoop Dogg.
Peter: Snoop Dogg definitely does more than make up for Gwyneth Paltrow.
Peter: Absolutely. Right. I don't use Gwyneth Paltrow. So I've got all these fun voices and, you know.
Peter: Nobody wants to use them. Right. So if I'm listening to something, just, you know,
Peter: like a Wired magazine article and it's kind of funny or something, I'll have Snoop Dogg,
Peter: you know, put me in the right mood. And then they've got some other voices. They're all just
Peter: really high quality, but the software still just lacks some really basic features. And I have sent
Peter: them a few suggestions. And now apparently I've sent them enough suggestions that they invited me
Peter: to have a meeting with them to discuss their product roadmap. I was like, okay, don't go.
Scott: Well, I can't. Don't go. The only person that's going to show up is their hit man on a building
Peter: about a half mile away. The Calendly link that they sent me doesn't work. So I can't.
Scott: Yeah. They need Calendify apparently. Oh my God. They need Calend-something. So,
Peter: I was a little disappointed, but not at all surprised when they sent me a non-working link.
Peter: But you know, like basic features, like being able to handle a PDF with whose text is in columns.
Peter: Right. That would be really good. And they got, you know, one of the developers said,
Peter: oh, well you can use our crop feature. So you have an, you can like trace rectangles around blocks of
Peter: text and make different zones. Okay. If I'm doing that for a single page, that's fine. But when I
Peter: have 135 page PDF book, I don't want to do that. Yeah. Besides you're trying to listen to an
Scott: article, it's not arts and crafts. You don't want to be tracing rectangles over stuff.
Peter: Boom. And on top of that too, they do have a feature where you can say define this for like
Scott: every page. Right. Which is good. But not all the columns are the same in every page.
Peter: Exactly. Because sometimes there will be like a top paragraph that spans the entire width of
Peter: the page. Right. And that will then get split in half. So, you know, it's like, okay, I think they
Peter: want to do the right thing, but I don't. You know what? This friggin, this thing is expensive.
Scott: I don't think they want to do the right thing. And all I can think is that they spent all the
Scott: money to, you know, promote their celebrity voices. I think that's where all their budget is gone.
Scott: Listen, so Gwyneth Paltrow does not give a about multi-column view. Okay. Peter. So just back off.
Peter: You're unreasonable. Yeah, but my man Snoop Dogg, he's all about the multi-column views, man.
Scott: That's not quite right, but it's pretty good. It's a little bit off, but I like it.
Scott: You need Snoopify because you... Snoopify. That'd be Snoopify.
Peter: That would have been what they should have named it was Snoopify. I would subscribe to that.
Peter: Anyway, so overall, you know, like I cannot give this product a buy recommendation. If we were back
Peter: in the My Mac days and I was writing a review, I would not tell you to go out and spend money on
Peter: this because it's so damn expensive. It basically comes out to like 10 bucks a month for a year long
Peter: subscription compared to something like Voice Dream, which was like, I think 20 bucks when
Scott: I bought it. And that was lifetime. Peter, why did you quit writing over two terabytes of reviews for
Peter: My Mac? It was over two terabyte of reviews, just so you know. Sorry. Why did you quit doing that?
Peter: So the one thing that was cool about being a My Mac reviewer was free stuff, right? They would send me
Peter: something. I would do my evaluation of it. And then I got to keep it to this day. What,
Peter: 10 years later? I still have the Bluetooth keyboard, the Can-X Bluetooth keyboard that I used.
Peter: So it was a nice perk, right? Now that said, if I was purely, you know, journalistic and I had
Peter: all the morals and integrity and stuff, I wouldn't be able to do that, right? I couldn't keep
Peter: that because it's essentially a bribe or something. But the thing about Tim,
Scott: here's the thing that I liked about Tim. He did have a clear cut sense of what's the right thing,
Scott: what's the wrong thing when it comes to getting stuff from people in product. He made it very
Scott: clear to them, you're not influencing our opinions and you can't ask us to say this, that, and the
Scott: other. We're going to say what we think. He was always very clear about that. Oh, absolutely. But
Peter: when it comes to accepting a gift, there's a little bit of a mental tax that goes into when
Peter: I receive this, I'm like, oh wow, I got a free keyboard. I don't want to say anything bad about
Scott: it. Regardless of the policy, it does affect your desire to bash somebody over the head.
Peter: Right. So that was it. Plus I just, you know, it was a time thing, you know, it was nice,
Peter: but you know, I was putting in like two, three hours reviewing something that was worth like,
Peter: you know, 30 bucks. So, you know, when it came time, like I was like, no, work is just keeping
Peter: me too busy. Didn't have enough time to do it, but it was fun. Anyway. Yeah. But anyway, so Speechify,
Peter: I don't know if you are interested in it, let me know to your listener. I will give you a referral
Peter: code where you get a discount and I get a credit as well. Again, you know, full disclosure, right?
Peter: You know, I'm getting paid to say that. Not really, but if you buy it, I would get a discount.
Scott: But if you just listen to Peter's review, you can tell that he's clearly not saying
Scott: amazing things about them just because he's got some codes to hand out.
Peter: But if you have simple structured documents.
Scott: Right. No multi-columns.
Peter: In one column, right? Well, what I do use it for mostly is websites, web page,
Peter: have it read web pages, articles to me. Here's the weird thing though, wired, right? You know,
Peter: if you look at any wired article, they always have like all of the top like five or six somewhat
Peter: possibly related articles embedded in the article you're using. If you switch to reader view,
Peter: those five or six or whatever related or unrelated articles that they're trying to get you to read
Peter: show up like 10 times throughout the course of the document.
Scott: Really?
Peter: When you go to reader view, they inject it over and over and over and it's like every
Peter: couple paragraphs, it'll be like, and you know, what Bankman Fried is doing is blah, blah, blah,
Peter: blah, blah. Folks have just discovered this. Scientists have just discovered this. Here's
Peter: why global warming is real. Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. Bankman Fried, da, da, da, da, da,
Peter: da, da, da. And then it's like, folks have just discovered this blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
Peter: and it's the exact same thing over and over again. So I can't use reader view with wired because they
Peter: inject their own self ads over and over again. And I pay for wired.
Scott: Can it really be that often, Peter, when you can't even tell me what they just discovered? I mean,
Scott: clearly they need to put it in there a few more times for you to get the message.
Peter: Oh dear God. Yeah. But I've been fast forwarding it. That's the thing that's kind of annoying,
Peter: but like listening to like long form articles like that, or Krebs on security articles or stuff like
Peter: that. I get those in the morning and I just have it read me that I like those. Can I just say,
Scott: Brian Krebs, you're doing God's work, but my God update your fricking website. It is shite
Scott: to read on anything but a laptop. And even that it sucks on. I mean, just speechify makes it better.
Peter: Have you heard of responsive design? My friend, speechify makes it better. I know, but it is just,
Scott: it's a relic. But other suggestions that I have given them was for instance, a pronunciation
Peter: dictionary, right? Because it can't say words like CISO and it, you know, it's like Sam Bankman fried.
Scott: It's always fried. Well, maybe he was fried. That might explain a few things. And there's always
Peter: content. Right? So when I start that Wired article, it's always skip to main content.
Scott: Peter, they're trying to set the mood. No, they're trying to get you all content and happy.
Peter: They want me to be content. Exactly. Just like my coffee is comfortable or comforting
Scott: or whatever it was. Comfortable. Right? So the voices that they have, again, the sound quality
Peter: is great, but there are some shortcomings into the pronunciation. You know, so there's other stuff.
Peter: So again, it feels like a, you know, a version 1.0 or a beta product. It doesn't feel like
Peter: something that's been around for, I guess a couple of years at least. It's got work to do,
Peter: but that said, you know, for the proper use case, the voices are just so much better to listen to
Peter: than the Ivona or NeoSpeech ones that, you know, Voice Dream has. Even without comparing them to
Scott: anything else, I can't listen to those anymore. Yeah. But if you could just take the, you know,
Peter: and I don't know where the voices come from. People. You know, I don't know if the speechified
Scott: people are coding their own. Peter, they come from people. Okay. Well, no, they come from AI.
Scott: These are AI generated voices, Scott. They come from Soylent Green. But I don't know, like,
Peter: where those voices come from as opposed to what, you know, where's the technology, what's the
Peter: secret sauce? Why can't the Voice Dream author get the same voices? Because if you just take Voice
Peter: Dream and give it good voices, you've killed Speechify. Speechify is just out because it's
Peter: a garbage program other than the voices. And Speechify as Voice Dream is an amazingly cool,
Scott: robust, mature program with garbage voices. So what you're saying is we need Snoop Dream.
Scott: We need Snoop Dream. So if Speechify and Voice Dream could just like come together and
Scott: get together and have a Snoop baby, you know what? Worse things could have happened. See here,
Peter: Hewlett Packard plus Digital Equipment Corporation plus Compaq.
Scott: Nobody ever had a baby pop out that looked like Snoop and said, Oh no, they said, we're rich.
Scott: Not only that, we have the coolest kid ever. All right. I want to plug,
Peter: before we get into what we're reading, what you're going to read. I have been having so much fun
Peter: listening to the guys over at BigSandwich.co. I am happily paying them $9 a month now for my
Scott: podcast subscription. Oh, you upgraded to the Big Cheese or whatever it is.
Peter: I'm Big Sandwich. Yeah, Big Sandwich. You may recall, I don't remember if we talked
Peter: about this on the show, but Scott, okay. We did. We just talked about it last episode.
Peter: Oh, but with the $2 and then $5, it's the same? Exactly the same. Well, I've had a beat. I don't
Peter: remember what we talk about anymore, Scott, because I'm always getting drunk when we're talking.
Scott: Now that we only put out an episode every two weeks, it was almost a month ago now that we
Scott: recorded that other one. I don't even, I don't know the timing. I don't know how that works,
Peter: but anyway, that's... Anyway, the folks behind The Weekly Planet and others now, they just hit
Peter: their 500th episode and I am a proud subscriber. Yes. I started listening to that on the treadmill
Scott: today, but when I got on the bike, I was doing an Apple Fitness workout, so I didn't finish it. But
Peter: yeah, I started listening to that. The beginning is hilarious. You should listen to it. Yeah. So
Scott: they have a, what does it sound like with 500 or 499 voices all over? All synchronized, yeah.
Peter: Just, it was static. It was great. Yeah. They're like, it sounds like the beginning of a mob riot,
Peter: a soccer riot or soccer match or something. So anyway, what, so from them, they have a section
Peter: every week called what you read, what we're reading, what we're going to read. So Scott,
Peter: what are you reading? What are you going to read? Speaking of Sam Bankman fried,
Scott: I am reading a book called Number Go Up. Number Go Up. And it is about the cryptocurrency insanity.
Scott: The thing that I want to read is about NFTs. It just shows how much of this stuff is religion,
Scott: Peter. When NFT came out, when NFT singular came out, when NFTs came out, we knew that they were
Scott: right. Like we knew it was an illusion. But the thing that I didn't realize is how many
Scott: celebrities, how many people were buying and endorsing these things.
Peter: So I want to read this to you. Go for it. Read it to me. Don't just read it to me. Read it,
Scott: read it to the listener. I will read it to you. Listener. I'm speaking directly to you. Imagine
Scott: that I'm standing in your house with a book in my hand. I think I just scared everybody away. Okay.
Scott: A common misconception, Peter, about NFTs listener is that the buyer owns a unique,
Scott: verifiable digital image. That is not the case. There's nothing stopping anyone from
Scott: right clicking on Justin Bieber's ape and downloading the image file to their computer.
Scott: The replica is indistinguishable from the $1.3 million original, and it's perfectly usable for
Scott: a profile picture. When a bored ape buyer pays hundreds of thousands of dollars, they're not
Scott: getting a digital ape cartoon. They're getting the ability to prove that they are the one who paid
Scott: hundreds of thousands of dollars for a digital ape cartoon. That's the difference. That's the thing
Scott: about NFTs that blew my mind once I realized you're not buying something that can't be
Scott: duplicated. You're just buying a piece of information in a blockchain in the ledger.
Peter: Yep. You just throw in some money out there and it just, I don't know, man.
Scott: So it goes on. Think back to that giant Excel spreadsheet in the cloud, the blockchain.
Scott: What if, in addition to keeping track of how many Bitcoins or Ethereum tokens each person owns,
Scott: it could also track who owns which ape picture. NFTs did that by adding an additional column.
Scott: There's a name, Zeke. There's a column that says Ethereum coins 103. There's a column that says
Scott: bored ape number 2735. The blockchain doesn't even hold the actual image file. It contains a
Scott: pointer to the image, which is stored elsewhere on the internet. In my case, my line in the
Scott: spreadsheet would have a link to bored ape 2735, which has an army helmet and heart-shaped glasses.
Scott: Anyone could look at that bored ape or even download the image, but only I
Scott: would be able to use the blockchain to prove that I owned it. It might not sound like much,
Scott: but ownership brought bragging rights during the crypto boom when people judged each other by the
Scott: size of their wallets. And one of the highest terms of esteem was degen for degenerate gambler.
Scott: NFT prices had gone up so much that crypto investors, celebrities, Hollywood talent agencies,
Scott: and fine art auction houses were calling NFTs the future of art, culture, and video gaming.
Scott: This is the part that blows my mind, Peter, is how many people
Scott: are we that I just don't understand our inability to see through shite anymore.
Peter: We're stupid. People are stupid. So no, they can't. I mean,
Scott: Most NFTs were part of collections of thousands of avatars that could be used as profile pictures.
Scott: This made them easier to show off and having so many nearly identical items made it easier
Scott: for traders to bet on their prices. The NBA had started selling basketball highlight videos as
Scott: NFTs, which were something like digital sports cards. Trading them in was so frenzied that
Scott: in March 2021, the Wall Street Journal featured a photo of a 27 year old who'd made $15 million
Scott: flipping these highlight videos. The same month, you may have heard of this company,
Scott: the same month, the auction house Christie's offered a collage of drawings by Beeple,
Scott: the most popular NFT artists. The drawings were childish and often misogynistic. Think Hillary
Scott: Clinton with a penis or Trump with boobs in bondage gear. But the reviews in NFT world were
Scott: rhapsodic. I look at my life as pre-Beeple and post-Beeple, said Noah Davis, the head of digital
Scott: at Christie's. Christie's auction house is not some fly by night stupid startup company full of
Scott: bros. And yet the head of digital there, Peter thinks of his life as pre-Beeple and post-Beeple
Scott: and goes on to say the same way the world thinks about before Jesus Christ and after.
Scott: For a few months, it seemed like anyone with a modicum of fame or crypto-savviness could
Scott: make huge money selling NFTs. It was even easier than creating an ICO back in 2017.
Scott: Jack Dorsey, the co-founder of Twitter, sold an image of his first tweet for $2.9 million.
Scott: A woman known online for selling jarred farts, Peter, started selling NFTs of her flatulence
Scott: instead. Her slogan was, imagine the smell. I don't know what to say. When I read that,
Scott: I thought to myself, you know, I think the planet is doing us a favor by heading us towards the
Scott: extinction event that we're headed for. When I read that picture of humanity, I don't want it
Peter: to survive. I want it to die. I'm having a hard time coming up with a counter argument to that.
Scott: I guess my question is why, why do we do this? And it's not just that why do people do it? Of course,
Scott: they're going to do it, but why do so many people buy in? Is it literally just all about the money?
Scott: Is it literally just about the money? And this could have been anything. And as long as it was
Scott: popular and money was involved, people, this many people, including celebrities, including
Scott: auction houses that you would think had a sterling reputation, but now they're, you know,
Peter: what is going on here? I don't understand. Greed. It's greed. But why can't people just
Scott: admit it instead of pretending like, Oh, this is the future of art. Oh, there's the,
Scott: why do they have to dress it up like that? Why do they have to pretend like it's so profound?
Scott: Why do they have to, it just boggles my mind. I, I, anyway, this book isn't that depressing
Scott: in general. That was the most depressing section of the book for me, but it's actually a really
Scott: good book. You should read it because the author of this book is basically obsessed with this coin
Scott: called tether, which was used to back, you know, a huge majority of the, of the cryptocurrency world.
Peter: Hence the name. It was tethered to real currency, right?
Scott: Supposedly supposedly. And he kept thinking, this is a Ponzi scheme. This is going to go down and it
Scott: kept not, and it kept not, and it kept not. And he was like, what am I going to write my book about?
Scott: And it's just a great story. But anyway, he follows the rise and fall of cryptocurrency
Scott: and just the insanity and all these people admitting, Oh yeah, yeah, this operates just
Peter: like a Ponzi scheme, but it's not a Ponzi scheme. It's not a Ponzi scheme. No, no,
Scott: it could never be that runs incredibly like one. Yeah. You would enjoy this book if you're at all
Scott: into technology and, or how people adopt stuff without thinking. I don't know. It's, it's a good
Peter: read. There you go. Cool. Well, Hey, I am starting to feel my beer. You got your hand in your cup
Scott: again. Yeah. It feels warm. So that's bad. So we should, we should move to wrap up, but what I'd
Peter: like you to do is send me that passage because I want to, as a bonus content for the listener,
Peter: I want to have Snoop Dogg read it. Oh my God. Yes. Yes. We can make that downloadable somewhere.
Peter: Yes. So just send that to me, dear listener. Send that to me, Scott, and I will send it to you,
Peter: dear listener. You can find that on our website, friendswithbrews.com.
Scott: It sounds to me like there's a way that you can make an audio file into an NFT.
Scott: I'm sure I can. Okay. Well then maybe we should sell an NFT of Snoop Dogg reading that passage.
Peter: For what? 0.5 Bitcoins? Does that sound fair? What's 0.5 Bitcoins go for these days? Like,
Peter: like a 95 cents? I don't know. Last, I think it was 95 cents about an hour ago. And so now it's
Scott: probably in about $9,500 right now. No, no, no. They don't bounce that high anymore.
Scott: They rebound slightly. Like they go back up a dollar or two and then they just keep going down.
Scott: Right now, according to Raycast, Bitcoin is worth $28,549.92.
Peter: What was its high? Ask Raycast. I don't know how to do that.
Scott: Okay. If you go, what was Bitcoin's high? And then hit tab.
Peter: I don't have the AI. I don't have the AI. Oh, you don't have the AI?
Peter: No, I don't pay for that. I am currently, other than like, you know, being the customer
Peter: of Microsoft, I'm not paying for any AI services at this point.
Scott: According to this, Bitcoin's all time high price was $68,789.63. It reached its peak on November 8th.
Peter: I thought it hit like 70 something. Yeah, but remember this, this might be,
Peter: okay. So let me say, um, GPT-4 says it's caught up on current events. So I don't know.
Scott: Well, so the tab, here's the thing about Raycast AI. If you type something in the Raycast bar and
Scott: hit tab to use that AI, the quick AI that's GPT-3. But if you do, if you open the chat window,
Scott: you can have GPT-4. So let me ask GPT-4. What was the last, what was the highest?
Peter: What was the highest high? Maybe you got the lowest high.
Scott: Gathering information. It still says November 8th, 2021. Okay. So if you Google for that,
Peter: what do you get? Bitcoin all time high price.
Scott: Yeah. It's it exceeded 65,000 USD in November, 2021. That's what I got in Statista.
Peter: Yeah. According to this, it was 69,000 all time high of nearly 69,000 in November,
Peter: 2021. So I would say that GPT got it right. Interesting. Statista shows it with a high of
Scott: about 61,837. See GPT said 67,566. Forbes says nearly 69,000, which 67,500 is nearly 69,000.
Scott: Yeah. It's weird. I'm on Statista.com and on their graph show an all time high of 61,837 in October,
Scott: but in the text they say it exceeded 65,000 in November. But if you look at that graph,
Peter: you don't see that, which is kind of funny. So numbers, yeah, graphs, graphs lie.
Scott: Graphs, numbers, who knew? Graphs, numbers. So there you go.
Scott: All right, Peter, speaking of graphs and numbers, you have a graph of a big red button that you like
Scott: to hit all the time. You like to show the listeners the graph of the big red button.
Peter: I like to hit that big red button. Big red button.
Scott: Oh, I was going to say the graph of the big red button only goes down. Too late.